<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Unconscious BIOS</title><link>https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Unconscious BIOS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 23:35:25 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I figured out how to post.</title><link>https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/not-so-dificil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 23:35:25 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/not-so-dificil/</guid><description>&lt;p>See? Not so hard!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>'So Corporate'? That's a good sign.</title><link>https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/2024-12-30-corporate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 01:49:56 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/2024-12-30-corporate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the course of my career I have often been in conversations with colleagues who lament how corporate our employer is becoming. &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re Microsoft now&amp;rdquo; was a recurring refrain during my time at Facebook, from 2012 to 2019. Let me explain how &lt;em>feeling&lt;/em> corporate is actually a blessing, because it means you&amp;rsquo;re at a growing company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is it good to be employed at a growing company? A growing company means everyone gets more scope; you don&amp;rsquo;t have to delicately politick just to get interesting work. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for any team to hit goals (e.g. increase growth by 15%) by riding the coattails of company growth. Greater revenue and more users mean a return on investment, so investors are happy, and teams have the resources and budgets they need. In general, the vibes are good and folks are optimistic when everyone feels like the company is on a good track and the best days are still to come.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>So you want to learn Mandarin Chinese?</title><link>https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/learn-mandarin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:49:56 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.unconsciousbios.com/posts/learn-mandarin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ask yourself why.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For financial advantage/business opportunity? &lt;strong>Don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong>. There was a study I saw (which I can&amp;rsquo;t find now) which compared the cost of reaching fluency (based on State Department estimates for how many hours of study required), compared with the economic benefits of having &amp;ldquo;fluent in mandarin&amp;rdquo; on a resume, and it was a net negative for Chinese. The most effective language to learn for native English speakers (economic/compensation advantage to knowing the language, divided by cost of language acquisition) is Norwegian. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many people who speak both, it&amp;rsquo;s close to English, and the Norwegian economy is bumpin&amp;rsquo;. To add, various Chinese policies (such as the 51% joint venture/IP sharing, and Government preference for local operations) make it difficult for foreigners to make a lot of money in business in China.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>